blueair.com 2017-06-30

# Privacy Policy | Blueair

Blueair AB respects your privacy and collects and otherwise process your personal data in full compliance with the data protection laws and regulations of European Union. 

This document explains what kind of information Blueair AB and its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively, “Blueair”) collects and stores, including personal data (i.e. data that can be reasonably linked to a specific individual or household) in connection with the operation of the blueair.com and blueair.com sub-domains (each, a “Site”) and air purifiers and other devices, products and services from Blueair (collectively, “Blueair Products”). Blueair Products include our mobile and web applications. Please note that this Privacy policy may change from time to time. We will provide notice of any changes on the website or by contacting you.

By using Blueair Products and services, you agree to allow us to collect and process information as described below.

**Collection of personal data**

Blueair collects your information in several ways. This information is used to provide users with Blueair Products and services, to allow us to understand how visitors navigate our Site, and to provide information and advertising that is relevant to your interests. Our Site does not knowingly collect or store any personal data about children under the age of 13.

Sign up and Setup: When you sign up to our Sites and set up Blueair Products we may request that you provide personal data e.g. name, address, phone number, email address, gender and any other information necessary to provide you with the Blueair Products and services. 

Where it is required by law or where Blueair otherwise deems it appropriate, Blueair will seek consent from you before we process your personal data. With your permission your email address may be used to send you news about Blueair Products, related services, products or promotions. We may use one or more service providers to administer these messages, but we do not share your email address with spammers or any other third parties without your permission.

In order to improve your experience over time and help troubleshoot any problems that you may encounter with Blueair Products, we record your device model, serial number and software version. To access your Blueair device over the Internet from a computer, a smartphone or a tablet, you will need to connect it to your Wi-Fi network. During setup, the device will ask for your Wi-Fi network name (SSID) and password to connect to the Internet. It will save this information on the device, along with your IP address, so that you can access it and control it from your computer, smartphone or tablet, and so that it can communicate with Blueair´s servers and download software updates.

When you sign up to a Blueair Site, you’ll be asked several questions in order to help us create an initial understanding of air quality settings that will keep you comfortable. For example, where in your home you’re installing the purifier. This information is used to personalise Blueair Products and your experience. You can change this information at any time through settings in the Blueair mobile application.

Device Usage information: If you have a Blueair purifier or other device, we record adjustments you make to the Blueair Product through the website or mobile application to learn your desired air quality levels in different situations. 

In order to improve your experience over time and help troubleshoot any problems that you may encounter with Blueair Products, we record technical information such as sensor and filter status. Every time your Blueair Product turns on and off, Blueair records the time and duration during which your device was on in order to offer you features such as usage history.

We collect air quality data (particulate matter (PM2.5), carbon dioxide, and volatile organic compound (VOCs) as well as temperature, air pressure, and humidity) from sensors built into Blueair Products. Sensors can detect air pollution and transmit data to the Blueair mobile application. 

Information about website and mobile application use:When you use Blueair mobile application, we may collect and record your unique device ID (persistent / non-persistent), hardware type, media access control (“MAC”) address, international mobile equipment identity (“IMEI”), the version of your operating system (“OS”), your device name, your email address (if you have connected to Facebook or Google+), and your location (based on your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address). This information is useful to us for troubleshooting and helps us understand usage trends. Similarly, we routinely record log entries (including information such as your IP address) and technical information (such as your browser type and version) when your browser, or Blueair Product contacts our servers. These log files are used for troubleshooting and are stored on our servers.

Like many websites, we and our third party partners analyze log file information and other data collected through cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technology, to collect information about your browsing behavior when you visit our website, including for example, your browser type, domains, page views, IP address, referring/exit pages, information about how you interact with our Site’s webpages and with third party links, traffic and usage trends on the service, etc. We use session cookies to keep you logged in while you use features of our web application; these disappear after you close your browser. We also use persistent cookies, which stay in your browser and allow us to recognize you when you return to the Site. We use this to remember your information so you will not have to re-enter it, to better understand how you use our website, to diagnose and fix technology problems, and otherwise enhance our services. In some of our email messages, we use a “click-through URL” linked to content on the Site. We track this click-through data to help us measure the effectiveness of our customer communications. We also use third party analytics tools (including Google Analytics) to assist us with analyzing and improving our service. Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies, but you may be able to change the settings to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you set your browser to reject cookies, parts of our Site may not work for you. Please note, depending on your type of device or browser, it may not be possible to delete or disable all tracking mechanisms on your device.

**Online Tracking and Your Choices:**

As discussed above, because we track website usage information through the use of cookies for analytic and internal purposes only, your selection of the “Do Not Track” option provided by your browser may not have any effect on our collection of cookie information for these purposes. The only way to completely “opt out” of the collection of any information through cookies or other tracking technology is to actively manage the settings on your browser or mobile device to delete and disable cookies and other tracking/recording tools. (To learn more about cookies, clear gifs/web beacons and related technologies, you may wish to visit allaboutcookies.org).

We permit third party advertising partners to use cookies and other technology to collect information about your browsing activities over time and across different websites when you use our Site. For example, we use advertising services provided by third party ad partners, such as Google Display Network and AdRoll, to market our services to you on other websites. Through a process called “retargeting,” each service places a cookie on your browser when you visit our Site so that they can identify you and serve you ads on other sites around the web based on your browsing activity. To avoid tracking by these third party ad partners, you can change your browser settings to reject cookies or to notify you when cookies are set and you could select the Do Not Track option on your browser, though we have no control over and cannot confirm whether these third party advertising partners honor the Do Not Track browser signal. Additionally, many advertising companies are members of the NAI or DAA and/or provide opt-outs on those industry pages at networkadvertising.org/choices or aboutads.info/choices.

Saved and Shared Content: Some Blueair Products may allow you to invite other people, such as friends or family, to share access to your content. We will ask you for that person's email address and automatically send an email invitation on your behalf. Blueair stores this information to send this email, to register your friend if your invitation is accepted and to track the success of our invitation services.You may save, and may choose to share certain content like video clips, live video streams, images, captions and comments for other people to access using the Services.  We will collect and store information that will allow us to save or share your content as directed by you through the Services.

Third Party Sites and Features: Our Site may contain links to other websites operated by third parties and may include social media features such as Facebook and Twitter buttons (such as “Like,” “Tweet” or “Pin”). These third party sites may collect information about you if you click on a link and the social media sites may automatically record information about your browsing behavior every time you visit a site that has a social media button. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the feature, not by our privacy policy. We do not control what information these third parties collect. Please review your privacy settings on your social media sites and think carefully before clicking on links which may take you to a third party website.

If you select an outside party for the purchase, installation or service of your Blueair Product and share your personal data, we cannot control the collection, storage or sharing of information collected by that party. For example, if you bought your Blueair Product from a retailer, they may collect personal data as part of the transaction. Or, the party that installed the device may retain information that you provided them with to assist them in servicing the device, if needed. Always check the privacy policies for any company that collects your personal data.

**Use of the collected Data**

We use information collected for purposes described in this Policy or disclosed to you in connection with our Products. For example, we may use your information to: provide, deliver operate and improve Blueair Products; understand you and your preferences to enhance and personalize Blueair Products to you and your experience; respond to your comments and questions and provide customer service; send you surveys, product related information, including confirmations, alerts, invoices, technical and other notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages; communicate with you about promotions, rewards, upcoming events, and other news about Blueair Products and services.

Blueair stores your personal data for as long as you remain a Blueair customer, in order to provide you with the services.

**Data sharing**

Under no circumstance do we rent, sell or otherwise share your personal data for any commercial or marketing purpose without asking your consent first. 

Upon the sale or transfer of the company and/or all or part of its assets, your personal data may be among the items sold or transferred. We will request a purchaser to treat your personal data under the privacy policy in place at the time of its collection.

We may provide personal data to a third party when so required under applicable mandatory legislation.

We may share non-personal information (for example, aggregated or anonymized customer data) publicly and with our partners. For example, we may publish trends about air purifier use, or air quality levels in homes. This information may also be shared with other users to help them better understand their air quality compared to others in the Blueair community, raise awareness about air quality issues, or help us generally improve our Products and system. We take steps to keep this non-personal information from being associated with you and we require our partners to do the same.

**Security**

Blueair uses commercially reasonable industry-standard physical, administrative, and technological methods while your data is transmitted over your home network and through the Internet to our cloud servers (e.g. including HTTPS, SSL, and 128-bit encryption). The methods may depend on your location and type of data. 

Blueair may process your personal data on servers located in the European Union and other countries that provide adequate level of personal data protection and security. Some information is processed and stored directly on the Blueair Product. All information is encrypted as it is transmitted to Blueair.

However, Blueair cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat our security measures or use your personal data for improper purposes. In the event that any information under our control is compromised as a result of a breach of security, we will take reasonable steps to investigate the situation and where appropriate, notify those individuals whose information may have been compromised and take other steps, in accordance with any applicable laws and regulations.

**International data transfers**

We may process your data outside the country where you live in (for example if you are an EU citizen, the servers of our cloud service providers may be located in the United States or otherwise outside the EU or the European Economic Area). In such cases, we will take steps to ensure that your personal data is processed lawfully and in accordance with this privacy policy. As a result, your personal data may be subject to legal requirements, including lawful requirements to disclose personal data to government authorities, in these jurisdictions.

We comply with the European legislation about international personal data transfers and DUS-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the US-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland.

Please note that by providing your personal data you consent to the transfer of your personal data between the European Union, United States and other countries.

**You rights**

You are at all times entitled to withdraw your consent to process personal data that you have provided to Blueair. Contact details for withdrawal of consent are set out below.

You may opt-out of receiving promotional emails from us by following the instructions in those emails. If you opt-out, we may still send you non-promotional emails, such as emails about your accounts or our ongoing business relations. You may also opt-out of receiving SMS notifications from us, either via SMS or online.

You can access, amend or delete your personal data held by Blueair through the controls in your account in the Blueair Products. After your information is deleted, backup copies may linger for some time before they are deleted, and we may retain certain data for a longer period of time if we are required to do so for legal reasons.

You can delete the information on the Blueair device by resetting it to the default settings (using Reset in the Settings menu) and on your mobile device by uninstalling the Blueair mobile application.

If you have any questions, please contact us at [info@blueair.se](mailto:info@blueair.se). Blueair AB, Karlavägen 108, 115 26 Stockholm, Sweden.
